afterworktech: we back
afterworktech: I like the new sound of the keyboard really relaxing.
Lana_Lux: 374 raiders from Lana_Lux have joined!
Lana_Lux: HeyGuys
Lana_Lux: oh we're in the library today?
Lana_Lux: LUL
afterworktech: ASMR stream <3
afterworktech: Thank you for the raid @Lana_Lux MrDestructoid
Lana_Lux: sounds good :)
afterworktech: If anyone is interested in tinygrad a very good intro to the project here https://youtu.be/kh2z9J_gXWg?&t=7440 | https://tinygrad.org/
H4nsec: H4nsec subscribed at Tier 1.
Fredirecko: Fredirecko subscribed at Tier 1. They've subscribed for 3 months!
xakerado: xakerado subscribed at Tier 1. They've subscribed for 4 months! Communists
satanic_pope: what's happening playa @georgehotz
Gadaros: Hey @georgehotz its always nice seeing you bro!! Whats up!?
AerisThor: I like the new keyboard's sound
khargoosh: khargoosh subscribed with Prime.
khargoosh: Hey George I wanted to say thanks for your Playstation work. I really appreciated getting Other OS back for a little while.
gliched_robot: I am writing a lora finetuning for tinygrad: https://github.com/Prakyathkantharaju/tinylora
gliched_robot: here is an answer from perplexity which does that: https://www.perplexity.ai/search/dataclasses-with-child-ue25LUoDRI6zZP_x5W5jyA?s=c
lava4o4: how come certain text in the command line is colored?
StackSample: emoneyLemon
OMGizGoZilla: hello George
Saas_1_: Both
lava4o4: i like this format
MDSZilla: Both
git_stash_pop: GoldPLZ GoldPLZ
lava4o4: and the other one as well
SekstiNii: can we shit on harvard now
StackSample: I liked the PianoTime bit
Saas_1_: this is nice for having it on in the background
lifeofAwais: I don't know everythign is relative to how my day went