mykyta_1: hey
lumma119: sup
whiterunknight: good morning
Shourikan: Yelo
hakobyte: yo
optionalflag: lets goo
moriartyblen: helo
lukasf6: Hello
sarah99___: ðŸ˜Ž here before submode (loser mode)
cantaim3: hi George
480i: hello Mr. Hotz
whiterunknight: did you buy the 5MW dam
obelixx0: obelixx0 gifted a Tier 1 sub to sarah99___! This is their first Gift Sub in the channel!
bojosos: Hello
sarah99___: Certified loser now BigSad
whiterunknight: hahahaha
sarah99___: ty 4 sub
RickAndMoreTea: how we doing yall
bojosos: Well he is absolutely right
MrKerow: alkXD
pepebruari: wrangle it in Georgie
madebyollin: sounds like it's time to refactor the linearizer
kalelite: Step 1: increase font size
sarah99___: Another certified George Hotz (noob) lesson Kappa . I.e chat will be lost after 10 mins
colonizethemoon: yo
djcodered__: lmaoooo
whiterunknight: :D
jjccccccj: Can you teach us react native?
bojosos: Good font size
whiterunknight: it’s a great font size
djcodered__: extra nice George ...
djcodered__: lmaooo
MrKerow: why you care about teaching others george ?
sarah99___: Karpathy era. I remember "Karpathy tries to actually teach you something, I just want to prove I'm smarter than you" GeoHotz
whiterunknight: George w hotz
jjccccccj: Meditation time?
bojosos: ratirlAlfred
bojosos: And we are already off HypeKEKW
djcodered__: I had a social studies teacher like that
jjccccccj: Those were the best classes tbh
sarah99___: she sounds 40+ so no
MrKerow: alkXD
alexberd24: peak content
bojosos: ratirlMeditate
sarah99___: BigSad we got GeoHotz Meditation before GTA 6 ðŸ˜­
whiterunknight: Namaste
sarah99___: you have to say the Namaste! It's what seals the calmness
bojosos: Gonna need that video in another 10 minutes
itsamarcos: meditation may be more effective than overcaffeination, guess I'll never find out though
sarah99___: Will captain throw us overboard (ban) ?
cuddles2000: cuddles2000 subscribed with Prime.
MrKerow: that's a name
itsamarcos: is there a goal for the tutorial? like fine tuning or running inference on a specific toy model?
kalelite: i didn't know we would go that noob
gliched_robot: gliched_robot subscribed at Tier 1. They've subscribed for 34 months! Looking forward to Tinycloud, how was your trip to find 1MW power stations?
cuddles2000: Nice outfit George. Looking the oppositie of disheveled. Shelved?
whiterunknight: I asked him that @gliched_robot he said to not get him started lol
gliched_robot: @whiterunknight  thanks! Sorry for repeating!
MustiFreak: hello
ABeautifuIDeath: hi
cuddles2000: What do you mean by "not computed yet" for the static data you set?
stoddlabs: stoddlabs subscribed at Tier 1.
stoddlabs: what is the benefit of Tinygrad being lazy?
gliched_robot: @cuddles2000 Because the ops are lazy. will run when they are needed. think similar to the python datetypes, it will assigned when needed to.
cuddles2000: So the lazy part in this case isn't "computing" as in math, it's about copying from memory to TPU
radon_90: radon_90 subscribed with Prime. They've subscribed for 3 months!
ABeautifuIDeath: ABeautifuIDeath subscribed with Prime. They've subscribed for 2 months, currently on a 1 month streak!
landepbs: and tag
TamagotchiCoder: hello dude
bojosos: This is a very tutorially tutorial
cuddles2000: Do duplicate calls do realize throw exceptions or is it a no-op?
IceLeo: IceLeo is gifting 10 Tier 1 Subs to georgehotz's community! They've gifted a total of 111 in the channel!
IceLeo: IceLeo gifted a Tier 1 sub to timichiban!
IceLeo: IceLeo gifted a Tier 1 sub to slouck!
IceLeo: IceLeo gifted a Tier 1 sub to 480i!
IceLeo: IceLeo gifted a Tier 1 sub to dfdx2!
IceLeo: IceLeo gifted a Tier 1 sub to lyrareturns!
IceLeo: IceLeo gifted a Tier 1 sub to thatjuandev!
IceLeo: IceLeo gifted a Tier 1 sub to brun2302!
IceLeo: IceLeo gifted a Tier 1 sub to kaljr!
IceLeo: IceLeo gifted a Tier 1 sub to Xewl!
IceLeo: IceLeo gifted a Tier 1 sub to jasondavies0!
TamagotchiCoder: Does it support Metal?
itsamarcos: I would just recommend having a clear goal for the tutorial, so that there is an end result to look forward to  makes the knowledge stickier too
itsamarcos: oops newline got removed there
dfdx2: @IceLeo Thanks for the gift sub!
smurfd0: <3
stoddlabs: If Pytorch isn't lazy, why is tinygrad? What benefits and trade offs are there?
itsamarcos: > what is the benefit of Tinygrad being lazy?  @stoddlabs it's so you can optimize the computation graph instead of executing every instruction greedily
bojosos: Torch has lazy stuff you just have to use them explicitly
stoddlabs: @itsamarcos so the idea would be to get all the context/steps for the job, then optimize form there instead of trying to optimize each step without the full context?
Mohaidoss: Mohaidoss subscribed with Prime.
Mohaidoss: Devtools pprint doesn't help make it prettier ?
firejjb1: if 2 UOp have the same src how is that printed
nuttyodin1: nuttyodin1 subscribed at Tier 1. They've subscribed for 26 months!
cuddles2000: That's super cool. It sounds like it would only copute t*4 once
smurfd0: print on line 95 you dont have the output for?
dontcrysomuch21: dontcrysomuch21 subscribed with Prime.
cuddles2000: I wonder how much CPU/memory gets spent trying to match operations to the global list to prevent duplicate compute
bojosos: What python is so magical
nuttyodin1: what are we doing today
stoddlabs: maybe it wouldn't be appropriate here, but maybe put why using Tinygrad makes sense over other libraries?
bojosos: But people in general don't make good decisions, they like being sold something shiny
itsamarcos: @stoddlabs exactly
cuddles2000: Is George threatening to break our leg?
def_stimulatedreceptors: def_stimulatedreceptors subscribed at Tier 2.
def_stimulatedreceptors: George, I am about to purchase tbox reds. I'm concerned on shipping internationally, especially to Aus. Have you had experience with shipping expensive large items to aus?
bambikapelo: x^2
cuddles2000: Yes
bojosos: yes
cuddles2000: AI support bot? Sometimes they don't suck now
djcodered__: lmaoooo I swear my friend thinks
djcodered__: If Im his CTO... he can text and email about random shit
djcodered__: koggin1Lynn2
smurfd0: maby keep output within """ """ comments
jjccccccj: what is a ramp
whiterunknight: a ramp for the noobs
cuddles2000: Is the generated C code just a reference or does it actually compile snippets of C as you run it?
def_stimulatedreceptors: Okay, that was all. I wanted to see the success rate of landing w/o damage. I have no trust issues w/ Tinygrad, just with shipping companies I've had bad experiences relating to expensive, hard to get hardware.  Thanks, good point. No I'm not looking for tinygrad to hold my hand and make me feel warm and fuzzy through each stage of the transaction. :)
whiterunknight: intel powered forklift
bojosos: Tiny customer service
boop322: boop322 subscribed with Prime.
def_stimulatedreceptors: It's not a money thing for me, I have a thing for freight handling morons breaking precious chips.. In Aus, our suppliers cut margins thin on consumer grade GPU's, so we have a limited market.  How that relates to my point, I suppose I have an phobia of GPU's being broken and wasted lol
whiterunknight: Hi
nuttyodin1: Hi, who is this now
whiterunknight: He needs his supplements
cuddles2000: George has gotten so zen
def_stimulatedreceptors: @cuddles2000 he has hasn't he
def_stimulatedreceptors: I think its called perspective
nuttyodin1: karpathy "empathy"
firejjb1: this is making sense so far
whiterunknight: Looking for shiny objects
nuttyodin1: who is the gurl
Ke_0: we don't
gliched_robot: Never ask chat!
cuddles2000: Ok so I actually have found this very straightforward and I've never worked with any of these libraries before, but I've been a software engineer for many years
def_stimulatedreceptors: Let sleeping dogs lie
0tt_1: Hello
whiterunknight: Very interesting podcast episode
gliched_robot: Increasingly, software has been abstracting away things. example torch! I think tinygrad is a breath of fresh air!
codingfisch: A fastai-like frontend would help...to attract script kiddies
gliched_robot: I have an Idea, bring in karpathy to stream for 1 hour and show him step by step. Good tutorial and stream.
whiterunknight: Your cam is still big, not that im complaining, but for the tutorial
cuddles2000: Does caching occur with the kernelized operations too? Like if two different operations produce the same kernel, is that computation run once? Like t+2+3 and t+1+4
wirtuosis: wassousu subscribed at Tier 1.
smurfd0: a good thing is that you can compare the output of prints to see that you do the same
stoddlabs: is the c code generated on the fly, and that's why the function name is E4n2()...?
stoddlabs: that explanation makes sense, ty
himynameischungus: I think VIZ is much more intuitive
smurfd0: nice to know the colors and the letters :)
himynameischungus: How stable is tinygrad's API? My perception is that multi is still fairly unstable
takeuchi_satomi: Ohhhh shiiii George is Streaminnnngggg lets gooooo. I was running out of george hotz archive vids on youtube to run in the background as I work XD
gliched_robot: I think I tweeted that it's crazy how derivative algebra is just 300 lines of code.
stoddlabs: so that means you could hypothetically create your own dag with all the ops and pass it to tinygrad to execute?
banceman: maybe add # %% to make each specific section runnable?
banceman: You need to end it too, I think.
banceman: No, just starting is enough. Sorry about that.
smurfd0: isnt this like one of those, i loose the name of them. ipython ehh
majorwho: had the same problem a week ago haha
majorwho: resolved it by using a venv
bojosos: This is a venv free strema
whiterunknight: I gave up on jupyter because of this kernel shit
majorwho: we love the Python undefined.undefined.undefined
smurfd0: jupiter playbooks what i was meaning
smurfd0: https://code.visualstudio.com/docs/python/jupyter-support-py
banceman: Do you have Jupiter installed via pip?
banceman: jupyter*
krakendmp: krakendmp subscribed at Tier 1. They've subscribed for 41 months!
majorwho: so ramp is like a tutorial/introduction i suppose?
whiterunknight: Yes
majorwho: nice
ForLoopInBash: ForLoopInBash subscribed with Prime.
hellscape48: coat makes him look like Chamath
gliched_robot: tiny box helping people hit SOTA https://x.com/jsuarez5341/status/1931369293536534572?s=12
majorwho: i think yeah
majorwho: its pretty simple
bambikapelo: this looks like haskell as a python dsl
gliched_robot: Did you also write about the graph view and debugging or that is a different tutorial ?
banceman: auto detect the best device is so nice
codingfisch: The pleb wants a short frontend. Something like "trainer.fit(...)"
himynameischungus: What do you mean by "time-based" visualisation? Like a profiler?
stoddlabs: this kind of reminds me of the Spark UI
jof343: If I cant probe once in a while how i'm I suppose to know i'm not talking to a brick wall?
whiterunknight: Damm the cops are outside
runnamucker4: WutFace
runnamucker4: manja manja, enjoy!
takeuchi_satomi: baiiiii
gliched_robot: bye boys!
majorwho: Have a good meal
takeuchi_satomi: When does the tinygrad and tinybox get to the level where company number 3 AI girlfriends becomes a reality Kappa
Giully3_14: Hi George, hope you are doing well. Thanks for sharing these, a lot to learn, have a nice day!
majorwho: Thank you for doing this!
whiterunknight: Made the font large and almost used a venv
takeuchi_satomi: On a more serious note seriously huge thanks for the stream and teachings!
rivetingco: conceptually simple?
dantedante33: "to commoditize the petaflop." i like your word choice herr
gliched_robot: There is no way anyone we can maintain torch code.
lsteacke: so you're john deere?
Zeevo: you just dont like dependencies
takeuchi_satomi: Smart people make things simple :)
n00n00n: You are wrong, King Terry can
ibarres: why is WMMA not a rewrite rule
banceman: I will go through the ramp. If I have any pointers, I will talk about it in Discord
stoddlabs: what is a warp?
govert72: Nice intro, thank you. Is trying to port an existing PyTorch-based model to tinygrad a good way to learn more? Should we expect better performance some day, or what other beniefits from doing this?
bojosos: @stoddlabs You should listen to his noob gpu tutorial
stoddlabs: @bojosos will look for it, I know nothing about GPUs
whiterunknight: @stoddlabs https://modal.com/gpu-glossary/device-software/warp
stoddlabs: @whiterunknight tyty
bojosos: I still remember the days of the 1000 line rule
pratikshit08: do tiinygrad make money
codingfisch: How many lines would be needed for tinygrad if solomonoff induction would be computable? ðŸ¤“
Zeevo: @georgehotz what excites you about python's future?
rivetingco: o7
majorwho: see ya
whiterunknight: Byeee
Gameplayer0618: o7
OetziOfficial: have a good one
takeuchi_satomi: See yaaas
runnamucker4: epic strim thank you!
def_stimulatedreceptors: thanks brother
SpongyBread: Thanks George!
malateman: what food?
pupscub: Will miss you
pupscub: have a great lunch
runnamucker4: what fodo?
def_stimulatedreceptors: When's new blog?
rivetingco: i love the heart, big heart
mokert2: Hi George, I played a little bit around with torch.linalg, unfortunately so far my impression is that it is not in good shape
def_stimulatedreceptors: no just new blog
majorwho: lex?
pratikshit08: what do think about software nowadays
robin_2723: are you gonna rub your belly after the lunch
21benzen: maybe we can upgrade you someday to a leather jacket
jjccccccj: has dwarkesh invited you?
bojosos: tiny.linalg?
FatherOfFamilyValues: â¤ï¸
def_stimulatedreceptors: ResidentSleeper
runnamucker4: feel like i need that as a slogan on a tshirt, merch incoming soon?
waena_: At what age did you stop being a consumer?
pupscub: Don't consume it use it to build!
itsamarcos: we're heading towards a two-class society
itsamarcos: whatever incentives created youtube shorts and tiktok are not going away
ibarres: best asmr
def_stimulatedreceptors: just don't be a drone, have some spark
dantedante33: we need to clip that.
runnamucker4: vswedHi
whiterunknight: signed